

Daniel Moreno Levy Software Engineer

Software Engineer USA / Spain Dual Citizen

+1 (707) 871-1906 danielmorenolevy@gmail.com

in linkedin | 🖸 github

## SUMMARY\_

Passionate about learning new skills and expanding my knowledge in order to solve information systems problems. I enjoy the challenge of finding concrete solutions to open-ended questions, carefully considering all available options, their advantages and disadvantages and executing the most appropriate. In my spare time I study Japanese, do sports and research technologies beyond the scope of those I typically use in my workplace.

### SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES
DEVELOPMENT ENVIRONMENTS
SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT INSIGHTS
FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES
DATA BASES
INFRASTRUCTURE
INTERPERSONAL
LANGUAGES

python | typescript | rust | golang | bash / zsh | solidity node / npm | poetry / pipenv | cargo | krew | linux | NixOS |
Design Patterns | CD/CI | UNIX Philosophy | Infrastructure as Code |
Django | Flask | Express | Nest | Vue | React | Gin | Lodash | Jest |
PostgreSQL | MongoDB | redis | Elastic Search | Graphql |
Docker | Kubernetes | AWS | Microservices | ArgoCD | Bull JS | RQ |
Positivity | Tenacity | Team Communication Skills | Fast-Learning Skills |
Native: English | Spanish | Advanced: Japanese, Nôken 2, Dec 2022

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **AUTOPAY**

November 2022 - Present

#### **TECH LEAD** - BACKEND ENGINEERING TEAM.

- Promoted to be responsible for the technical direction of the team.
- Refinement of work before it makes it to the team. Constant co-ordination with product team to bring requirements into reality.
- Investigate new technologies and create proof of concepts that could be good fits for the necessities of the business.
- Mentorship and guidance of team members.

# **AUTOPAY**

July 2022 - November 2022

# **BACKEND ENGINEER** - BACKEND ENGINEERING TEAM.

- Development of public API layer for car loan application submission.
- Modernization of legacy code. Rewrites into Typescript, redesign into an asynchronous distributed architecture based in AWS lambdas and SNS events.

BAMBU January 2022 - Present

## **BACKEND ENGINEER** - BACKEND ENGINEERING TEAM.

- Development of multiple backend services that constitute Bambu Robo Advisor.
- Deployment and maintenance of Kubernetes clusters that deliver financial services APIs to our various clients.
- Work with a diverse and international team, adapting Bambu Robo Advisor core to the specific needs of our clients from all around the world.

# **REBELLION PAY**

November 2020 - November 2021

### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER** - BACKEND ENGINEERING TEAM.

- Design and development of the systems that constitute the financial services of Rebellion Pay, as well as internal tools used to resolve customer incidents.
- Use of infrastructure virtualization and deployment tools, such as Docker, Kubernetes and Terraform, to guarantee 100% uninterrupted service to our customers.
- Integration of the backend service with multiple third-party APIs to develop new features, such as crypto currency trading or cashback rewards.

- Design and development of the projects transition from a monolithic REST service to a distributed micro-services architecture based on the NATS protocol, paying careful consideration to performance, data modeling and asynchronous services orchestration.
- Work in a multidisciplinary team under SCRUM methodology to achieve business goals guickly and efficiently.

### **MR HOUSTON**

August 2019 - November 2020

#### FULL STACK DEVELOPER - DEPARTMENT OF ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE.

- Full Stack Development of the web interface of an experimental application which mathematically measures the effect of news publications on share prices of IBEX 35 companies.
- Iterative refinement of the application, seeking attractive use cases for potential clients.
- Design of solutions for the multiple problems arising during development of the application (user interface refinement, query optimization, design of application state control systems, fixes for various unexpected behavior).
- Leadership and decision making skills, assignment of tasks to the rest of the team, setting priorities in order to meet deadlines.
- Research and implementation of productivity enhancement techniques, both strictly technical (DevOps, CI/CD) and organizational (Research-oriented SCRUM).

**OPTIVA MEDIA** 

June 2018 - October 2018

### **INTERNSHIP** - WEB DEVELOPER

- Developer in Media-Streamer, an ETL project for metadata enrichment of multimedia files through incoming data from multiple distinct sources, whose structures had to be consolidated into a single format.
- Experience as team member of a SCRUM organized software development project.
- Development of code in a production environment, with the responsibility of delivering client requirements within fixed times.

### EDUCATION

### Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

*September 2018 - June 2019* 

### **MASTER IN CYBER-SECURITY**

• **Graduate Project:** Research, development and deployment of an email spam filter using machine learning predictive model based on the Naive-Bayes algorithm.

### **COMILLAS ICAI**

September 2013 - June 2018

# **UNDERGRADUATE DEGREE IN TELEMATICS ENGINEERING**

- International Exchange Program: Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology, Terre Haute, IN (4th year of undergrad)
- **Undergraduate Project:** Comprehensive research of the security risks present in automobile control systems and implementation of a encrypted communication channel between the control components to alleviate the encountered issues. Sponsored by Rolls Royce, Indianapolis, IN.